<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julian Stephens</title>
    <link>https://julianstephens.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Julian Stephens</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://julianstephens.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Taoist Farmer</title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2021-01-30-the-taoist-farmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2021-01-30-the-taoist-farmer/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a Taoist parable of a farmer whose horse runs away. When his neighbors find out, they offer condolences for his bad luck. The farmer simply replies &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see&amp;rdquo;. Soon the horse returns with four more horses, and when this time he is praised for his good luck, the farmer replies &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.&amp;rdquo; The farmer&amp;rsquo;s son sets to work breaking in the horses but falls and breaks his leg. Once again, the neighbors lament the farmer&amp;rsquo;s bad luck only to receive the same reply, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data, Big Business, and the Construction of Privacy in Smart Cities</title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-12-08-big-data-big-business-and-the-construction-of-privacy-in-smart-cities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-12-08-big-data-big-business-and-the-construction-of-privacy-in-smart-cities/</guid>
      <description>** This work was originally an assignment for my CS 4873: Computing, Society, and Professionalism course at Georgia Tech. **
 Since the first Sumerian city-states were built in the early 4000s BCE, urban landscapes have simultaneously captured the peaks of human ingenuity and the depths of human depravity. Like no other construction, cities capture the ethos and ego of society. They are where the ball is pushed, great debates are had, and the fate of humanity is decided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice from the Last Four Years</title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-11-14-advice-from-the-last-four-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-11-14-advice-from-the-last-four-years/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m coming up on my last semester of my undergrad degree, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of reflecting on my time at Georgia Tech. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few things that I&amp;rsquo;d like to go back and tell 18 year-old me.
  Growth of any type is the product of friction. Change your mind, often. Information intake should be managed in much the same way as food intake. Getting the right nutrients makes all the difference in the quality of your output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Started as a Designer (Or Become a Better One)</title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-08-26-how-to-get-started-as-a-designer-or-become-a-better-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-08-26-how-to-get-started-as-a-designer-or-become-a-better-one/</guid>
      <description>One of the hardest parts of starting any new project or learning a new skill can be figuring out how to get started. There are thousands of blog posts, podcasts, and YouTube videos out there claiming to know the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; way to become a great designer. Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing, most of them are complete b.s..
You don&amp;rsquo;t need to go sell your firstborn for an Adobe CC license or start waking up at zero dark thirty for creative golden hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Southface Equity Evaluator</title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/portfolio/2020-04-06-southface-equity-evaluator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/portfolio/2020-04-06-southface-equity-evaluator/</guid>
      <description>Overview Southface is a nonprofit organization that focuses on the tools, technology, and policy that help create sustainable communities. One of the tools that they&amp;rsquo;ve created is the Equity Evaluator. Originally an Excel workbook, the Equity Evaluator helps organizations understand how their developments impact the surrounding communities. You can view it live here!
Purpose The goal of this project was to turn the Equity Evaluator into a modern web application. This would make it easier for Southface to distribute and monetize the tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Mental Models and Innovation</title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-04-06-understanding-mental-models-and-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/blog/2020-04-06-understanding-mental-models-and-innovation/</guid>
      <description>What is a mental model? The term mental model comes from Kenneth Craik&amp;rsquo;s book The Nature of Explanation. Craik said that we have internal models of the world that help us in decision-making, problem solving, task performance, and pretty much everything else that we do.
When people interact with the world, they notice patterns and start to anticipate them. Those patterns then combine and develop into an understanding of how systems function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://julianstephens.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstephens.net/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my humble abode! I&amp;rsquo;m a fourth-year B.S. Computer Science student at Georgia Tech with a minor in Psychology. This site is home to all of my passions and documents my intellectual adventures. My interests are varied and fluctuate constantly, so I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a list of some great content I&amp;rsquo;ve been consuming recently down below. This page is inspired by Julian Lehr&amp;rsquo;s media consumption journal.
 Podcasts
The Ezra Klein Show: Tyler Cowen Explains It All</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
